布 鲁 克 林
凯莉杂货店
凯莉小姐 待会我可以跟您谈谈吗
Miss Kelly, might I talk to you later?
要是你说的事情会给我添麻烦什么的
Not if what you're going to say will cause trouble for me
就别说
in some way or another.
九点钟的弥撒结束了 姑娘们
Nine o'clock mass is over, girls.
-给 请等一等  -谢谢
- Now. One moment, please.  - Thank you.
布雷迪夫人 今天早上您想要什么呢
Mrs. Brady, what would you like this morning?
请给我半打熏肉片
Half a dozen rashers, please.
就来 艾莉丝现在就拿给您
Of course. Eilis will get that for you now.
-轮到我了  -下一个就是你
-I was next. - And you still are.
-您要什么    -我想要点鞋油
- Yes?  - I need some shoe polish.
鞋油
Shoe polish?
那可不是周日供应的 对吧
That's not really a Sunday item now, is it?
这些顾客可都是来买东西做饭或泡茶的
These people need things for their dinner or their tea.
你为什么昨天不记着买呢
Why couldn't you have remembered yesterday?
你看起来昨天就得刷鞋了
Because it looks like you needed it yesterday.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
凯莉小姐
Miss. Kelly....
我没忘 想说什么 有话直说
I haven't forgotten. Spit it out, whatever it is.
我要动身去美国了
I'm away to America.
谁的主意
Whose idea was that?
纽约的弗洛德神父安排的
Father Flood in New York arranged it.
露丝以前跟他打过高尔夫球 他资助我去的
Rose used to play golf with him. He sponsored me.
他帮我找了份工作 办好了签证
He found me a job and got me a visa.
好吧 我们今后也不需要你了
Well, we won't be needing you back here.
我走之前 每周日都可以来上班
I could work every Sunday until I go.
不用 谢谢你了
No, thank you.
-你可怜的姐姐   -我姐姐怎么了
- Your poor sister. - My sister?
在这个国家母亲总是被丢下
Oh, mothers are always being left behind in this country.
可是露丝 这就是她的结局了 不是吗
But Rose ... That's the end for her now, isn't it?
下半辈子 都得由她来照顾你们的母亲了
She will be looking after your mother, for the rest of her life.
我真后悔没给神父弗洛德写信说说你 露丝
I wish I had written to Father Flood about you, Rose.
提我干嘛 我已经有工作了
Me? I have a job.
而你只有每周日去给刺头凯莉干几个钟头活
You had a couple of hours on a Sunday working for Nettles Kelly.
你不应该这么叫她
You should not call her that.
这名字已经很友好了
I think it's quite a kind name,
你不想想她实际上是个可怕的老巫婆
considering she's actually a terrible old witch.
好了 我不想再提她了
Well, I don't want to talk about her any more.
好啊
Good.
他们说那边夏天比这热 冬天比这冷
They say it's hotter there in the summer, and colder in the winter.
老天 她的衣服怎么办
What in Heaven's name will she do about clothes?
她会买新的 妈妈
She'll buy them, mother.
她不想浪费钱添置新衣
She doesn't want to be wasting her money on clothes.
她也没办法 她得在那儿待…
She won't have much choice. She'll be there for...
-你看起来美极了 南希  -谢谢
- You look beautiful, Nancy. - Thank you.
你漂亮到让我对这地方感到绝望
You look so beautiful it makes me despair of this place.
为什么
Why?
你是韦克斯福德郡最漂亮的女孩
Well, you're the prettiest girl in County Wexford.
你应该可以选择你想要的任何一个男人
You should be able to choose any man you want.
我们却盼着橄榄球俱乐部的乔治·谢里丹 能够多看你几眼
And we're hoping that George Sheridan from the rugby club looks your way.
-你说他会吗   -他当然会
- Do you think he might? - Of course he will.
我知道你喜欢他 南希 可他又不是加里·库珀 对吧
I know you like him, Nancy, but he's not Gary Cooper, is he?
Gary Cooper  美国演员 代表作 《约克军曹》
那些男孩们 打着发油 穿着休闲外套
And those boys with their hair-oil and their blazers…
他眼睛好迷人
He has beautiful eyes.
嗯 他会走进市集广场里漂亮的商店
Hmm. And he's going to come into a beautiful shop in the Market Square.
你怎么不穿那条蓝色连衣裙
Why didn't you wear your blue dress?
你是在问我 怎么不用心打扮吗
Are you asking why I didn't make more of an effort?
我想是因为我要离开这儿了
I suppose because I'm going away.
快来
Come on.
他往咱们这边看了两次了
He's looked over here twice already.
不会吧
He hasn't!
他朝我们走过来了
He's walking over here now.
你骗我
He's not!
我为什么要骗你乔治·谢里丹在干嘛
Why would I keep lying to you about what George Sheridan’s doing?
能赏脸跳支舞吗
Would you like to dance?
这就是你的全部家当吗
Is that really everything you own?
哦 艾莉丝 我应该把你照顾得更好的
Oh, Eilis. I should have looked after you better.
箱子里大部分衣服都是你买给我的
You've bought most of these clothes in this case.
这也是我离开的原因之一啊
That's one of the reasons I'm going,
我买不起自己的衣服
because I can't buy my own.
如果只是这样 我会把我所有的钱都开开心心地花在你身上
If it was just that, I'd spend every penny I had on you, gladly.
但我没法给你买一个未来
But I can't buy you a future.
你想要的生活 我买不到
I can't buy you the kind of life you need.
我懂
I know.
-不过你哪天会来看我的吧   -当然
- But you'll come see me there one day?   -Yes.
你会好好照顾自己的吧
And you'll look after yourself?
你不用担心我
You don't have to worry about me.
那我以后也会回家看看的 对吗
And I'll come home to visit, won't I?
因为我受不了 要是…
Because I couldn't bear it if...
你的鞋子还没打包呢
You haven't packed your shoes yet.
鞋子有点占空间
They'll take up a bit of room.
好了
There.
不好意思
I'm sorry.
起来
Off!
1号下铺
Number one. Bottom bunk.
这是我的位子 你在上面
That's mine. You're on the top.
简直是地狱 再不来了
This is hell. Never again.
不再去美国吗
Never again to America?
从美国回家就是个错误
The mistake was coming home from America in the first place.
我愿意做任何事 只要能不待在这可怕的船舱里
I'd do anything to get out of this horrible cabin.
-去抽根烟吧  -我不抽烟
- Let's go for a smoke. - I don't.
随便你吧 回头见
Suit yourself. I'll see you later.
说不好我能在头等舱遇到个好男人一起抽一根
Unless I find a nice man in First to smoke with.
很好 看来并不是每个人都因为天气预报而推迟了晚餐
It's good to see that not everybody's put off their dinner by the weather forecast.
据说今晚天气不好
It's supposed to be a rough one tonight,
所以其他乘客都没来吃晚餐
so none of the other passengers are eating.
顶多喝几勺汤 炖羊肉都没人吃
A few spoonfuls of soup, maybe, but not the mutton stew.
拜托开门
Please unlock it.
走开 门关着呢
Go away, it is closed.
对不起 我搞得臭气熏天的 还有这桶脏东西
I'm sorry about the smell, and the bucket.
别担心了 整艘船都臭死了
Don't worry. The whole boat stinks.
头等舱也一样
Even First Class.
我刚从那被赶出来
I've just been thrown out of there, by the way.
洗手间的门整夜都锁着
The bathroom door was locked all night.
噢 那些混蛋
Oh, those bastards.
好了 尽管不算舒适 但起码洗手间是我们的了
There. It won't be very comfortable. But at least it's ours.
开门
Open the door.
滚蛋 听到没 滚 蛋
Fuck off! Do you hear me? Fuck off!
要是昨晚你们友好一点的话 我们会公平行事
If you had been nice last night, we would have played fair.
你们现在没得用了 混蛋
Now you've got no toilet, you bastards.
好了 你去用洗手间吧 我去给咱们打些水
Go on, you can use it. I'm gonna get us some water.
你只许喝水
That's all you're allowed.
你要去美国生活吗
You going to live in America?
对啊
Yes.
证件和其他什么准备好了吗
You have papers and everything?
嗯 还找了一份工作
Yes. And a job.
你是怎么安排好这一切的
How did you manage to arrange all that?
不是我 有人帮我的 是我姐姐认识的一位神父
I didn't. Someone did it for me. A priest my sister knows.
那你什么感觉
And how do you feel about it?
爱尔兰的信寄给我要多久
How long do the letters from Ireland take to arrive?
我姐姐露丝说她会马上写信给我
My sister Rose said she'd write straightaway.
刚开始会觉得要等很久 时间长了就不觉得了
They take a long time at first, and then no time at all.
在美国有家人吗 朋友呢
You have family in America? Friends?
没有
No.
放心 你很容易能结识人
You'll meet people easy enough.
你住哪儿
Where are you gonna live?
布鲁克林吗
Brooklyn?
你怎么知道
How do you know that?
乱猜的
Lucky guess.
记住 有时能跟陌生人聊聊挺好的
Try to remember that sometimes it's nice to talk to people who don't know your auntie.
和陌生人聊天是这种感觉吗
That's what it's like?
就是那样
That's what it's like.
-我已经好几个小时没想吐了  -很棒啊 不是吗
- I've been sick for hours.  -Nice, isn't it?
我好饿
I am very hungry.
嗯 所以你才好几个小时都没想吐了
Hmm, that's why you haven't been sick for hours.
我们明天就能吃了
We'll eat tomorrow.
或者后天
Or the day after.
噢 亲爱的 我们得帮你改改造型
Oh, dear. We'll have to do something with you.
他们会把你隔离的
They'll put you in quarantine or something
要是你以这副面貌入境的话
if you try to enter the country looking like that.
别太花俏 你不能看起来像妓女
Nothing fancy. You mustn't look like a tart.
噢 好吧 看起来像妓女倒并不成问题
Oh, Well, looking like a tart isn't going to be a problem.
这件看起来不算糟
This doesn't look too bad.
我姐给我的
My sister gave me that.
穿这个搭一下
Wear it with this…
还有这件
and this.
准备开包检查
Open your bags ready for inspection.
也别看起来太天真了
Don't look too innocent, though.
我会给你上点口红和睫毛膏
I'll put some rouge and mascara on you.
也许再画个眼线
Perhaps some eye-liner.
你从队列里出来 谢谢 下一个 谢谢
You step out of the line please. Thank you. Next, please. Thank you.
护照
Passport please.
站直了
Stand up straight.
把鞋子擦亮 无论如何别咳嗽
Polish your shoes, and don't cough whatever you do.
不要粗鲁 别咄咄逼人 也别紧张兮兮
Don't be rude, or pushy, and don't look too nervous.
这边来
This way!
像美国人一样思考
Think like an American.
你得知道自己要去哪儿
You have to know where you're going.
欢迎来到美国 女士 请从蓝色门进
Welcome to the United States, Ma'am. Through the blue door, please.
下一个
Next, please.
上帝保佑我们 感谢我主慷慨赐予
Bless us, oh Lord, and these thy gifts which we are about to receive
我们即将享用的食物 阿门
from thy bounty through Christ our Lord, Amen.
阿门
Amen.
我看你收到一封信 戴安娜 有什么新鲜事吗
I saw you had a letter today, Diana. Any news?
她说德瓦莱拉先生眼睛又做了一次手术
Mr. de Valera has had another operation on his eyes, she says.
他已经去荷兰了
He's been in Holland.
我不想听报纸上就能看的消息
I don't want news that I can read in a newspaper.
不管怎样 我们认为德瓦莱拉先生是政治人物
Anyway, we would describe Mr. de Valera as "politics",
不是吗 凯赫夫人
would we not, Mrs. Kehoe?
我们不想吃饭的时候谈政治
And we do not like politics at the dinner table.
我们不喜欢
We don't.
眼科手术又不是政治
It's not politics to talk about eye operations.
但这眼睛是政客的眼睛
It is if the eyes belong to a politician.
而且我也不怎么喜欢谈医院的事情
And I do not like to talk about hospitals very much, either.
帕蒂 那面霜有没办法买到
Patty, did you have any luck with that cold cream?
没有 凯赫夫人
No, Mrs. Kehoe.
我问了卖化妆品的泰勒小姐
I asked Miss Tyler in Cosmetics.
还给她看了那广告
And I showed her the advertisement.
我可不想长途跋涉
I don't want to have to travel all the way
跑去曼哈顿就为了买一罐面霜
to Manhattan just for a jar of cold cream.
艾莉丝 能帮我看看巴尔托奇百货有没有吗
Maybe you could have a look at Bartocci's for me, Eilis?
好的 凯赫夫人
Yes, Mrs. Kehoe.
对啊 巴尔托奇百货准有
Oh, Bartocci's is bound to have it.
凯赫夫人 她根本不能肯定
She does not know for sure, Mrs. Kehoe.
她说巴尔托奇百货比韦博斯特百货好
She is only saying that Bartocci's is a better store than Webster's
只是为了气帕蒂
to get at Patty.
它们都很好
They are both very good,
你们这些姑娘能在里面工作都很幸运
and you girls are very lucky to be working there.
艾莉丝 你看起来是油性皮肤 对吗
Eilis, from the look of you, you have greasy skin, is that right?
你平时怎么护理的
What do you do about that?
就 呃 就清洗呗 凯赫夫人 用肥皂
Just... Well, I wash it, Mrs. Kehoe, with soap.
用肥皂没什么不好
There is nothing wrong with soap.
我猜主觉得肥皂就够好了
Soap was good enough for our Lord. I expect.
那主用的是哪个牌子呢 麦克亚当小姐
Well, which brand did he use, Miss McAdam?
圣经会告诉你这个吗
Does the Bible tell you that?
反正主是个男人
Our Lord was a man, anyway.
他可不在乎皮肤油
He didn't care about greasy skin.
姑娘们 就餐时不要再谈主的皮肤了 拜托
Ladies. No more talk about our Lord's complexion at dinner, please.
姑娘们会帮你找到合适的护肤品的 艾莉丝 是吧 姑娘们
The girls will help you find something suitable, Eilis, won't you, the girls?
巴尔托奇百货
-你好  -早上好
- Hi.  - Good Morning.
昨晚出去玩了吗
Did you go out last night?
-出去玩 宅在家的反义词  -没有
- Out. The opposite of in .  - No.
我昨晚和男朋友去看电影了
Well, I saw a movie with my boyfriend.
你看到什么了 桃乐丝
"What did you see, Dorothy?"
我看了《蓬门今始为君开》 艾莉丝 他们在爱尔兰拍的
"I saw The Quiet Man, Eilis. They filmed it in Ireland."
是吗 我家乡是爱尔兰
"Oh, I'm from Ireland".
我知道 所以我以为你会感兴趣
"I know you are, that's why I thought you might be interested."
谢谢你
Thank you.
稍等片刻
Shouldn't be a moment.
外面还热吗
Is it still hot out there?
从早上到现在我都没出去过
I haven't been outside since this morning
不过我猜可能
but I can tell that it might be.
挺热的... 看上去是这样
Very. It just..looks it.
的确挺暖和的
It's warm, yes.
多谢
Thanks very much.
你记住如果人家觉得这儿好就会再来
Remember ... If people like it here, they will come back.
所以你要像交新朋友那样对待每位顾客
So you treat every customer as if she's a new friend.
我会尽力的
I will try.
尽力是不够的 这是你必须做到的
It's not a matter of trying. It's what you have to do.
你会每天尽力穿内裤吗
Do you try to wear panties every day?
不会
No.
我是说我不是尽力穿上 而是肯定会穿
I mean, I don't..I don't try. I just put them on.
你明白我的意思了吧
You see what I'm saying?
- 明白 - 那就好
- Yes. - Good.
给我一份切片吐司
Can I get another sliced toast please?
做些热狗
Slice up some hot dog.
他们要中间切开的
They want them sliced down the middle!
你好 我要买单
Sorry. Could I have the bill please?
我希望当我走入天国之门时
I hope that when I go through the pearly gates,
迎接我的是你
the first sound I hear is you
用那可爱的爱尔兰口音找我买单
asking me for the check in that lovely Irish brogue.
他们有没有告诉你什么时候尼龙袜打折啊 艾莉丝
Have they told you a date for the nylon sale yet, Eilis?
这儿还没住过在巴尔托奇百货上班的女孩呢
We've never had a Bartocci's girl living here.
说不定我们能得到些内部消息
We might get some inside information.
我还没听到什么消息
I haven't been told anything.
就算你听说了也不会告诉我们的吧
I'll bet you wouldn't let on if you had.
她就是这种人 忠于老板多过朋友
She's that sort. More loyal to her bosses than to her friends.
像个红色特务
Like a Red spy.
哦上帝啊
Oh, dear God.
谢谢你把上帝扯进一段关于尼龙袜的谈话
I'll thank you to keep His name out of a conversation about nylons.
即使上帝无所不在也绝不会出现在巴尔托奇的打折特卖会上
He might be everywhere, but he's certainly not in Bartocci's on sale day.
对不起 凯赫夫人
Sorry Mrs. Kehoe.
你今天终于收到家书了 艾莉丝 真替你高兴
I was glad to see you finally got some letters from home today, Eilis.
- 真的吗 -恩
- Did I? - Em.
我忘了看了
I forgot to check.
你先吃完再看也不急嘛
They'll still be there after dinner.
哦 抱歉
Oh sorry.
亲爱的艾莉丝
Dear Eilis,
难以置信读这封信时你身在美国
It's hard for me to believe that you're reading this in America.
远隔重洋
Thousands of miles across the sea.
这边的大事情就是
The big news here is that since you left,
你走后妈妈就不再去刺头凯莉的店买东西了
Mummy has stopped shopping at Nettles Kelly's.
你知道的 她的面包不怎么新鲜
As you know, her bread wasn't always fresh.
东西都太贵
And she overcharge for everything.
人品还不好
And she's awful.
我没当面告诉她 没这个必要
I haven't told her to her face.There's no need.
她自己知道她的东西贵 又不新鲜
She knows that she overcharges and her bread's not fresh.
当然我们每天都谈起你
We talk about you every evening, of course.
我们想知道关于你的一切
We want to know everything.
你一定很忙 但即使你的信有两百页这么长
I'm sure you're busy, but even if your letters were two hundred pages,
你的母亲也会觉得不够长
they wouldn't be long enough for your mother.
照顾好自己 爱你
Take care of yourself. Love.
你这几天月事来了吗
Is it your time of the month?
那你是怎么了
So what is it?
去员工室休息一下吧
Take some time off now. Go and sit in the staff room.
对不起艾莉丝 都怪我不好
I'm so sorry, Eilis. This is all my fault.
我以为你不再需要人照看了
I was led to believe that you didn't need looking after.
弗兰科·巴尔托奇说你工作很棒
Franco Bartocci says you are doing great here.
玛·凯赫说你是她见过最好的房客
Ma Kehoe says you are the nicest lodger she's ever had.
- 怎么了 - 你叫她玛·凯赫吗
- What? - Ma Kehoe?
千万别当面这么叫她
Don't ever call her that to her face.
我已经忘了背井离乡的滋味有多苦
I'd forgotten just how bad it feels to be away from home.
我帮你在夜校报了名
I've enrolled you in a night class.
布鲁克林大学学记帐
For book-keeping. The Brooklyn College.
每周三次
It will be three nights a week.
第一学期的学费也帮你付了
And I've paid your tuition for the first semester.
- 为什么 - 干嘛问为什么
- Why? - “Why?”
你应该谢谢我啊
Not "Thank you"?
对不起 谢谢你 但是为什么呢
Sorry, thank you. But why?
我很吃惊像你这样聪明的人
I was amazed that someone as clever as you
在家乡居然找不到好工作
couldn't find proper work at home.
我在这儿呆了太多年了
I've been here too long.
都忘了爱尔兰啥样了
I forget what it's like in Ireland.
所以当你姐姐写信告诉我你的事
So when your sister wrote to me about you
我就说教会会想办法帮忙的
I said that the Church would try to help.
反正布鲁克林需要多些我们爱尔兰女孩
Anyway, we need Irish girls in Brooklyn.
真希望我能停止想回家的冲动
I wish that I could stop feeling that I want to be an Irish girl in Ireland.
我能告诉你的是 这种感觉会过去的
All I can say is that it will pass.
思乡病和其他毛病一样
Homesickness is like most sicknesses.
它让人难受 但终究会转移到其他人身上去
It will make you feel wretched, and then it will move on to somebody else.
泰勒诉标准燃气公司案
Now, Taylor versus Standard Gas Co
是过去二十年内最高法院审判的
is one of the most important corporate cases
最重要的商事案件之一
decided in the Supreme Court in the last twenty years.
它推动了了「深石原则」的确立
This was the case responsible for the Deep Rock doctrine,
它可以说是子母公司法领域的里程碑
so it's maybe the biggest milestone in parent-subsidiary law.
仅在公用事业整合的进程中
In public utility integration proceedings alone
就有成千上万的投资者
literally thousands of investors
因此受到影响
may be affected by its application.
你听得懂他说的这些吗
Did you understand any of that?
随便哪部分
I mean, a single word?
他都不用照着书念
He's not even reading from a book.
全在他脑子里
He just knows all this.
希望接下来的内容会简单点吧
Well, Let's hope the next hour is easier.
在美国火鸡是毁掉圣诞节的众多事物之一
One of the things that ruins Christmas in America is the turkey.
像在吃木屑
It all tastes of sawdust.
那麦克亚当小姐就吃芝士三明治
So that's one cheese sandwich for Miss McAdam,
她那份火鸡就分给大家了
and extra turkey for everyone else.
姑娘们 矜持点
Ladies, please.
艾莉丝 弗洛德神父把你的圣诞安排告诉我了
Eilis, Father Flood told me about your Christmas plans.
你不会要给无家可归的老年人发放午饭吧
Oh, you're not serving lunch to the old fellas who've nowhere to go, are you?
神父每年都请我们去 我们从来不去
He asks us every year. We always say no.
艾莉丝 你真是个圣人 那些人体味很大的
Ellis, you're a saint. They smell awful.
希拉知道他们有体味因为她要找的老公就在他们中间
Sheila knows how they smell because that's where she goes husband-hunting.
艾莉丝 你做的很好 很仁慈
It's a marvelous thing you're doing, Eilis. A Christian thing.
真希望有更多像你这样的人
I wish there were more like you.
请进
You can come.
大概会来多少人
How many are we expecting?
去年来了百来号人 今年可能更多
There were a hundred last year. There may be more this.
- 都是爱尔兰人吗 - 是的
- They all Irish? - All Irish.
他们为什么不回爱尔兰呢
Why don't they go home?
如果你这样年轻有才的女孩都没有发展空间
If there's nothing there for a clever young girl such as yourself,
他们这样的人就更没有生存可能了
there's gonna be even less for men like these.
有些人来了快五十年了
Some of them have been here fifty years,
和老家都联系不上了
they have lost touch with everyone.
圣诞快乐
Happy Christmas.
你好
How are you?
- 圣诞快乐 - 谢谢
- Merry Christmas. - Thank you.
就是他们这些人
These are the men who built ...
造了隧道 大桥 公路
the tunnels, the bridges, the highways.
没人知道他们现在靠什么生存
God alone knows what they live on now.
不好意思要打扰下大家
I don't want to interrupt the proceedings,
不过我相信大家都想谢谢
but I'm sure you'd all like to show your appreciation
辛苦了一整天的女士们
to all the ladies here for their hard day's work.
为表谢意
And by way of a thank you,
有位非常棒的歌手要为我们献上一曲
we have a great singer in the room with us today.
有请弗兰基
Frankie.
来客厅喝一杯吧
Would you like to come into the front room for a glass of something?
你应得的
You've earned it.
- 你挺过来了 - 嗨 也没那么糟啦
- You survived! - Oh it wasn't so bad.
- 圣诞快乐 - 干杯
- Happy Christmas! - Cheers.
麦克亚当小姐要搬走了
Now Miss McAdam is leaving us.
她去曼哈顿和姐姐一起住
She is going to live with her sister in Manhattan.
她住的是最好的一间房
She has the best room in the house.
就是地下室 那儿有独立的门
The basement. And it has its own entrance.
我只让某类女孩住地下室
Now, I can only let a certain kind of girl stay there.
我指的不是长相
Oh, and I'm not talking about looks here.
尽管我承认上天给麦克亚当小姐的长相
Although I will admit that God did give Miss McAdam an advantage,
在我考虑让谁单独住在地下室的时候成了优势
when I had to think about who I could trust to live down there.
艾莉丝你和她不同 你是漂亮女孩 但你也明事理
No no, you're a pretty girl Eilis. But you're sensible.
所以地下室给你住 就这么定了
So, you're having the room and that's that.
其他女孩不会有意见吗
Would the other girls not mind?
她们肯定有意见 不过她们对什么没意见呢
Oh, I expect so. What don't they mind?
姑娘们 你们会带桃乐丝去周六晚上的舞会吧
Girls, you'll take Dolores to dance with you on Saturday night, won't you?
有舞会吗
There's a dance?
在教区礼堂
At the parish hall.
不提供酒精饮料 不过你不需要那东西也能玩的挺开心
There'll be no alcohol, but you can have fun without it.
帕蒂和我这周不去跳舞
Umm, Patty and I aren't going this week.
我们去看电影
We're going to see a movie instead.
看电影桃乐丝肯定也乐意吧
Well, I'm sure Dolores would enjoy a movie just as well.
我很喜欢的
I would, very much.
纽约的电影比卡文那儿多多了
There are so many more movies here in New York than in Cavan.
是啊 完全没想到 本以为该是完全相反呢
Yes, surprising, isn't it? You'd think it would be the other way around.
欢迎你和我们一起去看 桃乐丝
Of course, you'd be welcome to join us, Dolores.
只要你不介意当电灯泡
So long as you don't mind being a gooseberry.
这么说你俩都在几天里奇迹般地找到男朋友了对吧
So you both miraculously found boyfriends over the last couple of days, did you?
我祝福你们这回不要再重蹈覆辙了
Well, I hope you have more luck with these than you did with the last few.
- 你去舞会吗 艾莉丝 - 我会去的 凯赫夫人
- Will you be going, Eilis? - Yes, Mrs Kehoe.
那你带着桃乐丝吧
Well, you can take Dolores, then.
没问题
Of course.
天哪 这儿人好少哦
God, there's nobody here.
人都没有怎么找对象啊
How are we supposed to get a fella if there's nobody here?
大部分人九点之后才来吧
I expect most people will come after nine.
来人还是男人
People? Or fellas?
总会来些男人啊
Some of the people will be fellas.
好想认识个男人啊
I'd love to meet a fella.
她们还是来了 两个骗子
They came! The liars!
真是一对贱人
What a pair of bitches.
老太婆就是这么叫她们的 她说她们都是贱人
That's what the old woman called them. She said they were all bitches,
除了你
apart from you.
你好啊
Well hello.
见到你们真好
Hello. It's good to see you.
我懂你
I can see why.
跟我们来
Come with us.
这样好看多了
There. That's better.
终于不像刚挤完牛奶进屋了
Now you don't look like you came in from milking the cows.
我以前看上去像吗
Is that what I looked like?
有点像 挤的是干净的奶牛
Just a bit. Nice clean cows.
一 二 三
1, 2, 3 ...
跳的不错
Not bad.
过一会我们再跳吧
Maybe we could have a dance later?
- 你说什么 - 过一会再跳
- Sorry? - A dance later.
好啊
Oh sure.
想跳舞吗
Would you like to dance?
你和那个教你跳舞的男的一起的吗
Are you here with that guy? The one who was teaching you to dance?
不是
No.
那你能和我跳舞吗
So would you dance with me?
他没教会我啥
I'm not sure he taught me anything.
没关系 跳舞的秘诀是要装作很会跳的样子
Doesn't matter. The secret is to look as though you know what you're doing.
哦 真希望有人早点告诉我
Ah. I wish someone had told me that years ago.
来吧
Come on.
- 你住哪儿 - 克林顿大街
- Where do you live? - Clinton Street.
真的吗 和我同路
Yeah? That's on my way home.
能陪你走回家吗
Can I walk you?
我会先答应你 然后告诉你原因
I'm going to say yes, and then I'm going to tell you why.
为了不让我误解你的意思吗
So I don't get the wrong idea?
算是吧
I suppose so.
有没有一个穿白衣的姑娘
Is there a girl in a white shirt
独自坐在那里
sitting on her own over there?
你不会认识她吧
You don't know her?
我认识
I do.
我们住在同一个寄宿家庭 她很烦人
She lives in my boarding house, and she's awful.
如果我跟你一起走了 我相信她会理解我的
If I leave with you, I'm sure she'd understand.
你这是在救我
You'd be rescuing me.
我知道了
I get it.
- 我不是爱尔兰人 - 听口音就不是
- I'm not Irish. - You don't sound Irish.
我得声明一下 我没有半点爱尔兰血统
I need to make this clear. No part of me is Irish.
我父母不是爱尔兰人 祖父母也不是 也没有爱尔兰亲戚
I don't have Irish parents or grandparents or anything.
我是意大利后裔 我爸妈都是意大利人
I'm an Italian. Well, my my parents are, anyway.
那你为什么跑来爱尔兰人的舞会
So what were you doing at an Irish dance?
意大利人不跳舞吗
Don't the Italians have dances?
跳啊 可我不想带你去意大利人的舞会
Yeah. And I wouldn't want to take you to one.
他们表现得太意式风格了
They behave like Italians all night.
什么意思
What does that mean?
- 噢 你懂的     -不懂
- Oh, you know. - No.
-他们的手势 - 太多了吗
- Hands. - Too many of them?
对于一个女孩子来说 我想是的
Oh,my. I guess it could seem that way, if it was a girl.
听着
Listen
我想开诚布公地告诉你
I want everything out in the open.
我参加爱尔兰人的舞会 是因为我真心喜欢爱尔兰姑娘
I came to the Irish dance because I really like Irish girls.
而我是当中唯一肯跟你跳舞的吗
And I was the only one who would dance with you?
噢 不是这样的
Oh, no, it wasn't...
是吗 那你跟很多姑娘都跳过舞咯
Oh, so you danced with loads of others?
我到了
This is me.
下周我能来接你去舞会吗 先去吃点东西好吗
Can I take you next week? Maybe get something to eat first?
行啊
That'd be nice.
晚安
Good night.
您的餐
There you go.
你不工作的时候做什么
So...What do you do when you're not working?
嗯 我上课 在布鲁克林大学
Well. There's school. Just, you know...Brooklyn College.
我在学记账
I'm studying book-keeping.
你想当簿记员吗
You want to be a book-keeper?
嗯 有朝一日我想当一个会计 不过 先做好簿记员吧
Well, I want to be an accountant one day. But, yes, book-keeping first.
哇 难吗
Wow. Is that difficult?
我说得够多了 跟我说说你修管道的工作吧
I'm talking too much. Tell me about plumbing.
-修管道的事情你已经知道的够多了 -我什么都不懂
- You know enough about plumbing already. - I don't know anything.
你只要知道水龙头会渗水 厕所会堵塞
You know that taps drip and toilets get blocked
这样就够了
and that's all you need to know.
我对记账一无所知
I don't know anything about book-keeping.
好吧 说起来挺复杂的
Well.There's a lot to it.
当然有很多数学
There's all the maths, of course,
但不太复杂
but that's not so complicated.
复式记账法要花好些时间去掌握
The double entry system, that takes a while to get used to.
我们还要学公司法 这门课最让我头疼
And we study company law, too, and that terrifies me.
我们要阅读一家在三十年代破产的保险公司的相关信息
So we had to read about an insurance company that went bankrupt in the 1930s,
学习涉及的相关法律问题
and all the the legal issues that went along with that...
她会打高尔夫 打得非常好
She plays golf, and she's really good at it.
如果她去了上周六的舞会
And if she'd been at the dance last Saturday,then...
你不会多看我一眼 因为露丝太美了
I don't think you'd have looked at me twice, because Rose is beautiful.
我有点担心 你的菜都没有动
I'm worried you haven't eaten anything.
光顾着说话了
Too busy talking.
你们两个丫头今天又是哪出
What is the matter with you girls now?
有问题的不是我俩 凯赫夫人
Nothing is matter with us, Mrs Kehoe.
是不是因为艾莉丝找了个男友
Is this all because Eilis has found herself a young man?
艾莉丝的男友吗
Eilis'  young man?
我们不知道 她对此事只字不提
We didn't know. She won't say anything about it.
她干嘛要对你们这些爱传八卦的家伙提起呢
And why should she, to you awful gossip-mongers?
反正我在周六晚上遇到了这个小伙子
Anyway, I met him on Saturday night ...
那会他来找艾莉丝 他是个绅士
when he called for Eilis, and he is a gentleman.
凯赫夫人 快给我们多讲讲他
Will you tell us what you know about him, Mrs Kehoe?
我们知道他长得挺帅
We know he's quite nice-looking.
我不太喜欢他穿的鞋
I didn't like his shoes much.
他的鞋怎么了
What on earth is wrong with the shoes?
颜色很滑稽
They were a funny color.
我跟你们说
I'll tell you this much:
我要请弗洛德神父举办一场布道训诫你们轻浮的危害
I am going to ask Father Flood to preach a sermon on the dangers of giddiness.
我现在把轻浮看作是第八宗罪
I see now that giddiness is the eighth deadly sin.
女人的轻浮和男人的懒惰是一样的罪恶
A giddy girl is every bit as evil as a slothful man,
轻浮的笑声更不能容忍 立刻 不许再笑了
and the noise she makes is a lot worse. Now, enough.
好 考虑一下
Yeah. Think about it. You can...
好好好
Yeah,yeah.
我只是想陪你回家
All I want to do is travel home with you.
不去吃饭 也不去喝酒 什么都不干
No food, no drink, no nothing.
我知道你要学习 然后好好睡一会儿
I know you got to study and get some sleep.
我只要送你回到家 说句晚安
I'll take you to your house and say goodnight.
不然我等不了那么久了
Otherwise, it's too long to wait.
我想问你一件事 你听了会说 噢 太早了
I want to ask you something. And you're gonna say, "oh, it's too soon."
我还不太了解他 我们只是见了几次
"I don't really know him well enough, we've only been out a couple times."
我想问的不是什么坏事 只不过大部分男人都会在
Oh, it's nothing so bad. It is just something that most guys...
请直接问吧 你这样让我紧张
Please just ask. You're beginning to terrify me.
噢 好 你愿意哪天来我家吃饭 见见我的家人吗
Oh. Sure. Will you come for dinner and meet my family sometime?
这就是你要问的吗
That's it?
我愿意
I'd love to.
你喜欢意大利菜吗
You like italian food?
不确定 我没吃过
Don't know. I've never eaten it.
意大利菜是世界上最棒的美食
It is the best food in the world.
那我有什么理由不喜欢呢
Well, why would not I like it?
你心情不错哈
You're in a good mood, huh?
是啊 怎么了
Yes, why?
只是 我喜欢你这个样子 我不知道怎么形容
It's just... I like how you're being, I don't know the word.
当你对每件事都配合的时候
When you go along with everything.
顺从
Amenable?
是的 顺从
Yeah. Amenable. OK,
趁着你还顺从的时候
so while you're being amenable..
我们这周能在你没有课的晚上去看场电影吗
Can we go see a movie this week when you're not in night classes?
我愿意看两场
I'll sign up for two movies.
- 真的吗 - 真的
- Really? - Yes.
就算第一次约会不顺利
Even if the first date is a disaster,
我会再给你一次机会
I'll give it another chance.
感觉上是这样的
It certainly feels like it,
但这是我第一年在这上班 所以我不知道如何判断
but this is my first year, so I don't know how to judge.
祝贺你 度过了第一个在纽约的冬天
Well congratulations. You survived your first New York winter.
噢 并不是那么糟糕
Ah, it wasn't so bad.
是吗 爱尔兰更冷吗
Really? It's colder in Ireland?
噢不 这儿更冷
Oh no, it's colder here.
我们评判冬天的标准就是看冬天有多冷
Over here, that's how we judge the winter. On how cold it is.
可是你们有暖气 到处都是 你们只有在室外冷
But you have heating. Heating everywhere. You're only cold outside.
倒也是
I guess that's true.
-谢啦    -祝你一天愉快
- Thank you for your help. - Have a good day.
艾莉丝 你跟变了个人似的
Eilis! You're like a different person!
你怎么做到的
How did you do it?
也许我可以把你的心得传授给下个想家的姑娘
Maybe I can pass some advice on to the next poor girl who feels that way.
我有男友了 一个意大利人
I met somebody. An Italian fella.
噢 不 我不会传达这样的建议的
Oh no. I'm not passing that on.
我宁愿她们想家也不想她们失恋
I'd rather have them homesick than heartbroken.
他常常谈论棒球吗 还是把他妈妈挂在嘴边
Does he talk about baseball all the time? Or his mother?
没有
No.
那得留住他 纽约再没有这样的意大利男人了
Then keep him. There isn't another Italian man like him in New York.
打住 记着 这是容易的 因为上面还没加酱
Hold it. Now remember You're getting off easy, because we haven't got sauce.
是的 你要记住酱汁会四处溅 所以要慢慢来
Yeah. You have to remember that the sauce flies everywhere, so take it slowly.
每次我看到动作有问题的时候 我就说 “溅了”
I'm gonna say "Splash" anytime I see problems.
-好主意    -我可以开始了吗
- Good idea. - Can I start now?
-可以 -开始
- Yeah! - Go!
溅了
SPLASH!
你刚刚溅到他妈妈 他爸爸 还溅到墙上了
You just splashed his mother, and his father, and the walls...
再来一次吧
Let's go again.
亲爱的露丝 我想最重要的消息是
Dear Rose, I suppose the most important news
我交了个男朋友
is that I have a boyfriend
我清楚 他不如百货公司的工作重要
He isn't as important as Bartocci's ...
也不如夜校的学习重要
and my evening classes, I know that.
但我想告诉你这里发生的一切
But I wanted to tell you everything that is going on.
请别跟妈妈说 你知道她会有什么反应
Please don't mention it to Mummy though. You know what's she like.
他为人得体又友善 他有一份工作并且很努力
He's decent and kind, and he has a job, and he works hard.
我们每周三去看电影
We go to the cinema on Wednesdays
周六他带我去弗洛德神父的舞会
and he takes me to Father Flood's dance on Saturdays.
我每天都想着你和妈妈
I think of you and mother every single day.
但是托尼令我觉得我在美国有了新生活
But Tony has helped me to feel that I have a life here.
在遇到他之前 我没有
I didn't have before I met him.
以前 我的身体在这里 而我的生活停留在有你们的爱尔兰
My body was here, but my life was back in Ireland with you.
现在在远隔重洋的地方开始了新生活
Now it's halfway across the sea.
这很了不起 不是吗
So that's something, isn't it?
对了 我得提醒你小心弗兰基
Oh and I’d better warned you about Frankie.
最小的那个
He's the little one.
是的 他少年老成
Yeah. He's eight going on eighteen.
他既友善又机灵 但总是话很多
He's nice and he's smart, but he's been talking
他有好多话要说给你听
and he's talking about all the things he's gonna to say to you.
- 说什么呢 -不知道 可能是任何事情
- What sorts of things? - We don't know. Could be anything.
我试了给他钱
I mean, I swear I tried to pay him money to
让他出去跟朋友打球
go out and play ball with his friends.
我爸也威胁他不要乱来
And my dad, he threatened him,
可是我想他正巴望有机会制造麻烦
but I think he's looking forward to causing trouble
这样好痛快挨顿揍
so much so he'll happily take a beating.
这就是我家了
This is us here.
准备好了吗
Ready?
你在哪儿学的这么吃意面的
Hey, how did you learn to eat spaghetti like that?
我有上课
I've been taking lessons.
上课 在课堂上吗 有这样的课吗
Lessons? Like, in a class? You can do that?
也许我可以教你
Maybe I could teach you.
不 不 戴安娜 我的舍友
No, no. Diana, who lives in the boarding house with me...
她为我做了意面 逼我学着在不弄得一团糟的情况下吃掉它
cooked me some spaghetti and made me try and eat it without making a mess.
你们在爱尔兰吃什么 爱尔兰炖菜吗
So, what do you eat in Ireland? Just Irish stew?
不止 我们
Not just. We...
首先我想说我们不喜欢爱尔兰人
So first of all I should say that we don't like Irish people.
打住 打住
Hey, hey ...
-弗兰基 - 怎么了
- Frankie! - What?
我们不喜欢爱尔兰人 人尽皆知的事实
We don't! That is a well known fact!
弗兰基 为什么呢
Why Frankie?
因为一伙爱尔兰人把毛里齐奥揍伤了
Because a big gang of Irish beat Maurizio up
他缝了好几针
and he had to get stitches.
但这事根本没人管
And because all the cops round here are Irish,
因为所有的警察都是爱尔兰人
nobody did anything about it.
这事也许有另外一面
There are probably two sides to it.
可能我当时说了一些不该说的话 可是我现在想不起来了
I might have said something I shouldn't, you know, I can't remember now.
不管 就是因为他们打了你
No, because they beat you up.
无论如何 他们可能不全是爱尔兰人
Anyway, they probably weren't all Irish.
对啊 他们只不过全是红头发 大粗腿而已
No. They just had red hair and big legs.
给我起来 失陪一下
Raise up! Excuse us.
我唯一能替他讲的好话就是他可能是我们之中唯一可以上大学的人
All I can say in his defence is that he's the only one of us who'll get a college education.
前提是他能把嘴闭上
If he can keep his mouth shut.
托尼说你在上大学
So, Tony tells me go to college.
只是夜校而已 我想当一名簿记员
Oh, just night classes. I want to be a book-keeper.
我喜欢现在百货商场的工作
I like working in the shop well enough,
但我不想一辈子待在那里
but I don't want to be there forever.
很好
Good.
对不起 艾莉丝 我是个白痴 一个粗鲁的白痴
I'm sorry, Eilis. I'm an idiot.I'm a rude idiot.
托尼提出过赛季开始后带你去艾比兹球场看比赛吗
So has Tony offered to take you to Ebbett's Field when the season starts?
你喜欢棒球吗
You like baseball?
他从没提到布鲁克林道奇队吗 一次都没有吗
He never mentioned the Dodgers? Not even once?
托尼 你怎么了
Tony, what is the matter with you?
你们知道为什么吗 光顾着干这个了
You know why? Too much of this.
不管怎样 到了夏天你只能去艾比兹球场才能看到他了
Anyway, you'll have to go to Ebbett's Field if you want to see him in the summer.
他们对你来说这么重要吗
They're that important to you?
这么说吧
Put it this way.
如果我们的孩子决定要支持扬基队或巨人队的话 我会很失望的
If our kids end up supporting the Yankees or the Giants, it would break my heart.
我也是
Mine too.
她可没在笑哦 托尼 我想已经晚了
She's not laughing, Tony. I think it's too late.
她支持扬基队
She's a Yanks fan.
你说什么呢 你怎么搞的
What are you talking about? What's wrong with you?
他是扬基队球迷
He's a Yanks fan.
我爱你
I love you.
我... 谢谢你 今晚很开心
I..Thank you for the evening. It was lovely.
对不起
Sorry!
我已经用完了
I'd finished.
希拉 问你点事情可以吗
Sheila can I ask you something?
你为什么还没结婚
Why are not you married?
因为我丈夫离开我 跟别人在一起了
Because my husband met somebody else and left me.
抱歉
Oh I'm sorry.
额 你会再结婚吗
And ... Well, would you get married again?
- 是不是有人跟你求婚了 - 不 不算吧
- Has somebody asked you? - No, not really.
我不会刨根问底的
I won't ask what that means.
希拉
Sheila?
我会再结婚吗
Would I get married again?
不 我打算一辈子住宿舍 跟别人抢厕所
No. I want to be waiting outside the bathroom of my boarding-house, forever.
我当然会再结婚
Of course, I do.
为此我每周都去参加那个讨厌的舞会
That's why I go to that wretched dance every week.
我想有自己的家
I want to be waiting outside my own bathroom.
会有个脾气不怎么好
While some bad-tempered fella,
耳毛都露出来的家伙
with hair growing out of his ears
坐在马桶上看报纸
reads the newspaper on the toilet.
那时我就会希望我能回到这里 和你聊聊天
And then I'll wish I was back here, talking to you.
明天见
I'll catch you tomorrow right?
艾莉丝 抱歉
Eilis! I'm sorry!
我以为你不来了
I did not think you were coming.
我猜到你会这么想
I know. I thought you were gonna think that.
所以我无论如何都想赶过来
That's why I wanted to be here. No matter what.
我想告诉你
I need to say something...
你能不能 咱们能不能先谈点儿别的
Can you... Can we talk about something else ...
到了凯赫夫人那儿再说
until we get to Ms. Kehoe?
- 这不是 - 拜托
- It's Not ... - Please?
那么 见到你的十分钟之前
So. Ten minutes before I'm supposed meet you ...
我还站在从老奶奶的天花板渗出来脚踝深的脏水里
and I'm standing ankle-deep in sewage that's pouring through this old lady's ceiling.
所以 就算你想请我回家喝咖啡
Yes. Even if you were thinking of inviting me in for a coffee.
我也得拒绝 为了你好
I would have to say no, for your sake.
所以你怎么在十分钟里修好它的
So how did you fix it in ten minutes?
我没有 那十分钟我都在跟老奶奶解释
I didn't. I spent the whole ten minutes explaining to the old lady
我得去个地方 然后我再回来
that I had to be somewhere and I'd be back.
她不想放我走
She didn't want to let me go.
所以天花板还在渗脏水吗
So the sewage is still pouring through the ceiling?
额 六英寸深和一英尺深的脏水也并没啥差别对吧
Oh, what's the difference between six inches of sewage and a foot?
你让我说我想说的吧 我觉得你不会介意
Let me say what I want to say. I don't think you'll mind.
好吧
Okay.
还记得吗 在你家吃完晚饭 你告诉我你爱我
You remember that after I had dinner at your house, you told me you loved me.
我当时不知道该说什么
Well, I didn't really know what to say.
但我现在知道了
But I know what to say now.
我考虑过了 我喜欢你
I have thought about you. And I like you,
我喜欢跟你在一起 还有
and I like being with you and ...
也许 我对你也有同样的感觉
Maybe, I feel the same way.
所以下次你再说爱我的时候
So the next time you tell me you love me,
如果还有下次
if there is a next time ...
我也会说 我爱你
I'll say I love you too.
-你是认真的吗 -是的
- Are you serious? - Yes.
卧槽 原谅我爆粗口了 但是
Holy shit! Excuse my language, but...
我还以为你要谈别的
I thought we were having a different kind of talk.
我可以回家了吧
Can I go home now?
-你爱我吗 -是的
- You love Me? - Yes.
但是别再问我其他问题了
But don't ask me anything else,
也别提什么咱们的孩子会变成道奇队的粉丝
and don't talk about our kids being Dodgers fans.
你是想让孩子喜欢洋基队吗
Oh what? You want kids who like the Yankees?
托尼 拜托 别逼我
Tony, please don't push me.
好吧 我道歉
All right. I'm sorry.
亲爱的艾莉丝
Dear Eilis,
非常谢谢你的尼龙袜
Thank you so much for the nylons.
巴尔托奇的包装纸让它们看上去格外漂亮
The Bartocci wrapping paper makes them look so glamorous.
似乎跟这边比起来 任何事物都很新奇 令人兴奋
It seems everything is so exciting and new compared to here.
我迫切地期待 有一天你能带我见识这一切
I can't wait for you to show it all to me one day.
艾莉丝 你知道我的心与你同在 即使我不在你身边
Oh Eilis, you know I'm by your side, even when I'm not.
你真不可思议 我必须这么说
Well. You're marvelous, that's all I have to say.
而且在我看来你的考试不止是通过了
And it looks to me as if you didn't just pass those exams.
你是轻松通过
You, you flew through them.
我已经记不得上次有人来这儿报喜是什么时候了
I can't remember the last time anyone came here with good news.
我攒了一些钱
I've saved some money.
交得起下一年的学费 还能还给你上年的
I'll be able to pay for next year's tuition and pay you back for last year.
我教区的某个人已经替你交了
One of my parishioners paid.
他需要造福人类 我不会告诉你原因的
He needed to do something for mankind, and I won't tell you why.
他自己也还没走出迷林
He is not out of the woods yet, either.
所以他可以为你下一年出学费
so he can cough up for next year, too.
我想知道他被困在什么样的迷林
I'd love to know what sort of woods he's in.
我知道你想 但不会从我这里知道
Yes, I'm sure you would, but you won't hear it from me.
学业有成 还告别了单身 艾莉丝
Qualifications and a boyfriend, Eilis.
你已经不是去年冬天那个想回家的悲催小姑娘
You're not the miserable young girl who wanted to go home last winter.
那些事听上去真遥远
Seems like years ago.
我认为这是第一次
Now, I think this is the first time ...
住在这儿的姑娘们中
any girl of mine
有人破天荒通过了考试
has ever passed an exam, while living here.
你告诉托尼了吗 艾莉丝
Have you told Tony yet, Eilis?
当然
Of course.
他准备带你出去庆祝吗
And is he taking you out to celebrate?
我们周末会去科尼岛
We're going to Coney Island at the weekend.
-天哪   -怎么了
- Oh, boy! - What does that mean?
你有没有泳衣
Do you have a bathing costume?
- 没有 我准备去买... - 你有太阳镜吗
- No, I was going to get one... - Do you have sunglasses?
- 没有 - 你需要太阳镜
- No. - You need sunglasses.
我听说今年 如果你在沙滩上不戴着它
I read that if you don't have them on the beach this year
人们就会说闲话
people will talk about you.
他们会说什么啊 希拉
And what exactly will they say, Sheila?
这才是重点 凯赫夫人
That's the thing, Mrs. Kehoe.
你永远不会知道 因为他们并不当着你的面说
You'd never know, because they'd never say it to your face.
哦上帝啊
Oh, dear God!
戴安娜说得对 艾莉丝 你应该好好斟酌你的装扮
Diana's right, though, Eilis. You need to think carefully about your costume.
托尼第一见你穿这么少 你不会想让他失望的
It's the most Tony will ever have seen of you. You don't want to put him off.
你下面得剃干净
You'll have to shave down there.
我给你一把管用的剃刀
I'll give you a razor that will do the trick.
你的屁屁暂时没问题
You're all right there for the moment.
大多数意大利男人都喜欢丰满的体型
And most Italian men appreciate the fuller figure.
但是 夏天你还是要注意点
But watch yourself, over the summer.
你肤色白皙 黑色对你来说太暗了
The black's too dark for your pale skin.
咱们来试试绿色
Let's see you in the green.
看那边
Look at that thing.
你怎么不告诉我要把泳衣穿在衣服里面
Why didn't you tell me to put my costume on underneath my clothes?
我以为你知道
I thought you'd know.
好了
Right, I'm ready.
- 托尼 - 咋啦
- Tony! - What?
过来
Come on.
亲爱的露丝 感谢你的来信
Dear Rose, Thanks for your letter.
听到你高尔夫锦标赛的消息我很高兴
I was happy to hear about your golf tournament.
你肯定高兴坏了
You must have been really pleased.
我依然思念你和妈妈
I still miss you and mother,
我每天都在想你
and I think about you every day.
然而我觉得 这是自我来到美国之后第一次感受到
But I think I can say that for the first time since I've been in America,
真正的幸福
I'm really happy.
这大部分要归功于托尼
This is a lot to do with Tony.
周末他带我去看了布鲁克林道奇队的比赛
At the weekend he took me to see the Brooklyn Dodgers,
他热爱的棒球队
the baseball team he loves.
他们输了 这让他很生气
They lost, so he was annoyed.
我也开始在找文职工作
But I've also started to look for office work, too.
这周我去面试了
I had an interview this week ...
在布鲁克林的一家纺织品公司
at a textile firm here in Brooklyn.
露丝
Rose?
谁能想到 在一家会出两个簿记员呢
Who'd have thought that there would be two book-keepers in the family?
露丝
Rose?
我很快就能攒够钱回家看你和妈妈
I'll soon be able to afford to come home and see you and mummy.
露丝
Rose!
露丝 上帝啊
Rose? Oh my God!
上帝啊
Oh God!
露丝
Rose?
不
Oh no!
稍等
A moment.
太突然了 我想她可能是生病了
It was sudden. I think perhaps she was ill,
她自己知道 但她没有告诉任何人
and she knew she was ill, and she didn't tell anybody.
会发生什么
What will happen?
能发生什么呢
What can happen?
-她什么时候下葬 -明天
- When will they bury her? - Tomorrow.
-不等我吗   -不等
- Without me. - Without you.
你离得太远了 艾莉丝
You're too far away, Eilis.
我到底为什么来这里呢
Why did I ever come here?
露丝希望你能过得更好
Rose wanted a better life for you.
她很欣慰你做得这么优秀
She loved how well you were doing.
但我再也见不到她了
But I will never see her again.
是这样吗 神父 我再也见不到她了
That's right, isn't it, Father? I will never see her again.
你知道的 我相信你们会再见的
You know that I think you will.
她会一直守护着你 在你余生的每一天
And she will be watching over you, every day, for the rest of your life.
喂 妈妈
Hello? Mommy?
能听见我说话吗 喂
Can you hear me now? Hello?
听不太清
I can't really hear you.
无论如何 葬礼上没有下雨
Well, the rain held off, anyway.
她的高尔夫俱乐部成员都来了 每一个人
And the whole of her golf club came. Every single one of them.
把屋子都挤满了
We had a real houseful afterwards.
你还在听吗
Are you still there?
在
Yes.
人们都很爱她 艾莉丝
People really loved her, Eilis.
同事 邻居 每一个人
Her friends from work, the neighbours, everybody.
没人知道该对我说什么
Nobody knew what to say to me.
你爸爸去世时 我告诉自己 我不能太过悲痛
When your daddy died, I said to myself that I shouldn't grieve too much
因为我还有你们两个
because I had the two of you.
你去美国的时候 我也这么跟自己说
Then when you went to America, I told myself the same thing
因为她还在这儿陪着我
because she was here with me.
但你们都走了 艾莉丝 没人在我身边了
But everyone's gone, Eilis. I have nobody.
我受不了了 托尼
I can't bear it, Tony.
你是不是想回家了
You wanna go home, I guess.
如果我回去了 你怎么办
And how would it be for you, if I did go home?
我会每天担惊受怕
I'll be afraid, every single day.
- 你担心我不回来吗 - 是的 家毕竟是家
- Afraid that I wouldn't come back? - Yes. Home is home.
我不确定我还有没有家了
I'm not sure if I have a home anymore.
你明天不去上班 是吧
You are not going to work tomorrow, are you?
做完弥撒后 我能带你去个地方吗
After the Mass, can I take you somewhere?
就是这里了
This is it.
如果可以的话 我们在这里盖上五间房子
We're gonna build five houses here, if we can.
爸妈会拥有其中一间
And mom and dad, they are gonna have one,
因为我妈总是想要一间带后院的房子
Cos ma always wanted a house with a backyard.
把其中的三个卖掉 剩下那一个
We'll sell three. And the other one...
我兄弟们问我想不想要 我说是的
My brothers they asked me if I wanted it and I said that I did.
所以 我觉得我想说的是
So, I guess what I'm saying is
你想和我一起在长岛这里生活吗
if you want to live out here on Long Island?
我知道现在这儿看上去并不是太好
I mean I know it doesn't look like much right now,
但是周边其他的地都已经卖光了
but all the land around here has been sold,
所以我们不会孤独
so we wouldn't be on our own.
会架电话线 通电 什么都有
And there would be telephone cables, electricity and everything.
我们会创办一个公司
We're gonna set up a company,
一个建筑公司 我们三个
a building company, the three of us.
我负责管道 劳伦斯做木工
And I'm gonna do the plumbing and  Lawrence is gonna do the carpentry.
别不说话
Don't go all quiet on me.
至少告诉我你会考虑考虑
At least tell me you'll think about it.
我不需要考虑
I don't need to think about it.
就回去一个多月 这样会让她好过一点
It's just for a month or so. I know it would make her feel a little better.
你愿意在走之前嫁给我吗
Will you marry me before you leave?
你不相信我会回来吗
You don't trust me to come back?
嫁给我 嫁给我吧
Marry me! Marry me!
我们不需要告诉任何人
We don't have to tell anyone.
我们赶紧结了 就我俩知道
We just do it quickly, just keep it between us.
你为什么想要这样做呢
Why do you want to do it?
因为不这样的话 我会疯掉的
Because if we don't, I am gonna go crazy.
我现在发誓不也一样吗
Would a promise not be the same?
如果你可以发誓的话 结婚对你也不难
If you can promise, you can easily do this.
所以就是这里吗 这就是你住的地方吗
So this is it? This is where you live?
是的 如果你弄出一点噪音 她会把我赶出去的
Yes, and if you make one tiny noise she'll evict me.
天哪 天哪
Oh, man! Oh, man!
现在没必要担心了 待在我身边
Oh, there's no point in worrying now. Stay with me.
-你想玩吗 -当然
- Do you want to play? - Yes, sure.
好的 球棒马上就好
Alright. Here we go, one bat coming up.
球给我 准备好了吗 手抬起来
I'll take that, alright. You ready? Hands up.
哇 直接打到三垒底线
Oh, right down to the third-base line.
他是不是打扰到你了 因为连我都觉得他吵
Is he annoying you? Because he is annoying me.
没有没有 我有个弟弟跟他一样大 你是爱尔兰人吗
No no no. I got a brother the exact same age? Hey, are you Irish?
有这么明显吗
Is it so obvious?
我只是马上要跟一个爱尔兰的姑娘结婚了
I'm just about to marry an Irish girl,
所以我更容易注意到
so I guess I notice it more.
布鲁克林有好多爱尔兰人啊
There are a lot of you in Brooklyn.
有时候我觉得好像爱尔兰都没人了
Sometimes it seems as though there can't be anybody left at home.
你的未婚妻是爱尔兰哪里的
Where is your girl from?
恩尼斯科西 在威克斯福德郡
Enniscorthy, in County Wexford.
我妻子好像有亲戚住那
I think my wife has family there.
嗨 艾莉丝 过来一下
Hey, Eilis! Come here for a second.
安东尼·菲欧雷洛和艾莉丝·蕾西
Anthony Fiorello and Eilis Lacey.
将来我们会告诉孩子们我们是秘密结婚的吗
Will we ever tell our children we did this?
可以留到某个纪念日上说
Maybe we'll save it for some anniversary.
不知道他们会怎么想
I wonder what they'll think of it.
南希
Nancy!
你好迷人
You look so glamorous!
我就说吧
I told you so.
-露丝的死我很遗憾 -谢谢你 你怎么样
- I'm so sorry about Rose. - Thank you. How are you?
不是吧
No!
我早知道了 但我希望南希能亲口告诉你
I knew. But I wanted to let Nancy tell you herself.
-我好高兴你能来参加我的婚礼 -我能吗
- I am so glad you can come to the wedding. - Can l?
你母亲已经代你接受了我的婚礼邀请
Your mother accepted the invitation on your behalf.
-什么时候   -八月二十七
- When is it? - The 27th of August.
你明晚能跟我和乔治出来玩吗
Will you come out with George and me tomorrow night?
安妮特也想见你
Annette wants to see you, too.
我不介意你出去
Oh, I don't mind.
我得给你找把钥匙
I'll have to find you a key.
我可不想起来给你开门
I don't want you getting me out of bed.
我们都很想听听纽约生活是什么样子
We all want to hear what life in New York is like.
我会尽量想出点东西来跟你们分享的
I'll try and think of something to say.
我回纽约的船票是二十一号的
I'm booked to go back to New York on twenty-first.
你可以多待一周 见证你最好的朋友结婚吧
Oh, you can wait an extra week to see your best friend married.
我不敢相信 你永远没办法认识我丈夫了
I can't believe I'm married to someone you'll never know.
你一定会喜欢他的 我相信
But you'd like him. I know you would.
他很贴心 很幽默
He's sweet. He's funny.
而且他的眼睛非常美
And he has got these wonderful eyes that…
我好希望事情不是现在这样
I wish everything were different…
现在轮到 来自库什的奥图尔太太
So, now. Mrs. O'Toole from Cush.
我们必须要回信吗
Do we really have to do this?
收到一封吊唁信跟收到生日礼物不一样吧
Getting a letter of condolence isn't like getting a birthday present, is it?
如果这位来自库什的奥图尔太太给你回信
What if Mrs. O'Toole from Cush writes back
来感谢你的感谢信呢
To thank you for your thank you?
那我就再回一封感谢信
Then I'll thank her.
你也愿意后半生都这样寄信收信吗
And you'll be happy to spend the rest of your life like that?
反正我也没别的事情可做
It's not as if I have anything else to do.
也没有别的人可以说话
Nor anybody else to talk to.
就和来自库什的奥图尔太太写写信呗
It might as well be Mrs. O'Toole from Cush.
那你想让我写什么
What do you want me to say?
应该是南希和安妮特到了
That would be Nancy and Annette.
去吧
Off you go.
好好玩
Enjoy yourself.
艾莉丝 这是吉姆·法瑞尔
Eilis, this is Jim Farrell.
很高兴认识你
It's a great pleasure to meet you.
我们可以去康诺特酒店的酒吧
We could try the Connaught Hotel bar.
可能橄榄球俱乐部的几个伙计会在那
There may be a few of the fellas from the rugby club there.
好的
Okay.
你们就天天跟橄榄球俱乐部的那帮人待在一起吗
Do you have to be with other fellas from the rugby club all the time?
也不是 只是南希不允许我们跟你讲话
No. But Nancy told us that we wouldn't be allowed to talk to you.
因为你们之间有太多话要说了
Because you have too much to say to each other.
所以我们只是去找几个伴罢了
So we're just looking for company.
哦 这样
Oh, well.
你不喜欢橄榄球俱乐部的那帮人吗 艾莉丝
Do you not like the fellas from the rugby club, Eilis?
我不太喜欢他们 乔治
I don't particularly, George.
我刚到美国的时候
When I first went to America,
恩尼斯科西的任何东西我都很想念 除了他们
I missed everything about Enniscorthy, except one.
我们也不是全都一样的
We are not all the same.
你们看起来都一样 穿着运动夹克 抹着发油
You all look the same. It's the blazer and the hair-oil.
南希 安妮特怎么没来 还有他怎么来了
Nancy, where is Annette? And why has he come?
他人很好的 别对他太刻薄了
He's very nice, so don't be too hard on him.
这是跟凯特琳·卡西迪订婚的那个吉姆·法瑞尔吗
Is this the same Jim Farrell that was engaged to Cathleen Cassidy?
发生了什么
What happened to her?
是他提了分手 吉姆觉得她并不是真正爱他
He broke it off. He didn’t think she was serious about him.
他难过了好一阵儿 不过现在都过去了
He was very upset for a while, but he's over her now.
南希 我是要回美国的
Nancy, I'm going back.
但是你在这儿的时候可以找点乐子嘛 不是吗
But you can have a bit of fun while you're here, can't you?
走吧乔治
Come on George.
你母亲还好吗
How is your mother?
她很伤心 最近老得很快
Well, she's sad. And she's got much older very quickly.
那件事太糟了
It was a terrible thing.
我们都去参加葬礼的弥撒了 我父母和我
We all went to the funeral mass. My mother and my father and myself.
我之前不知道呢
I did not know that.
我母亲跟你姐姐一起打高尔夫 她很喜欢你姐姐
My mother played golf with her, you know. she is very fond of her.
你姐姐的死是我记忆中这镇上发生的最悲伤的事情
It was the saddest thing that happened in the town that I can remember.
-谢谢你 -你们俩快来啊
- Thank you. - Come on you two.
-那些摩天大楼怎么样 -那是曼哈顿
- What about the skyscrapers? - But that is Manhattan.
我住在布鲁克林 我的工作在布鲁克林 如果我出去玩 也在布鲁克林
I live in Brooklyn and I work in Brooklyn. And if I go out, I go out in Brooklyn.
所有的摩天大楼都在河对面
All the skyscrapers are across the river.
-你在美国的生活听起来并不是很光鲜啊    -因为它的确不是
- You don't make it sound very glamorous. - It's not, really.
连那个 唉你叫它什么来着
Not even… What do you call it?
你工作的那个百货
The department store where you work?
巴尔托奇百货 店里卖的东西都很好
Oh, Bartocci's? Well, it sells lovely things,
不过大部分我都买不起
but I can't afford many of them ...
而且我也不是很喜欢那份工作
and I don't like the works.
那你想做什么
What would you like to do?
我想做露丝之前的工作
I want to do what Rose did.
我想在办公室里跟数字打交道
I want to work in an office and deal with numbers.
你应该去戴维斯那问问
You should call in at Davis's.
他们还没能找到接露丝班的人
They haven't managed to replace Rose, you know.
婚礼一结束我就会回纽约了
I'll be going back to New York straight after the wedding.
但走之前你应该也想要挣点钱吧
But you might want to earn a little money in the meantime.
我相信你去上班他们一定会很高兴的
I'm sure they'd be glad to have you.
少来 你只是想让艾莉丝留下来
Oh, you just want her to stay.
我只是在替艾莉丝着想
I am only thinking of Eilis.
你听到了吗艾莉丝 他想着你呢
Did you hear that Eilis? He's only thinking of you.
就是这里
That's it, that's it...
-晚安    -晚安
- Good night. - Good night.
-再见 -再见
- See you. - See you.
再见
Bye.
-你今晚过得怎么样    -挺不错的 谢谢
- How's your evening? - It's very nice, thank you.
车里那个跟他们一起的是吉姆·法瑞尔吗
Was that Jim Farrell I saw on the car with them?
是的
It was.
你知道吗 他的父母要搬到乡下养老去了
His parents are moving, you know. They're retiring to the country.
他会一个人住在镇子上的大房子里
He'll be in that big house on his own.
是吗
Is that right?
对某些人来说 他条件挺不错的
It's a catch for "someone".
妈妈 晚安
Goodnight Mommy.
-嗨 艾莉丝 - 嗨 布伦南太太
- Hello Eilis. - Hello Ms. Brennan..
我喜欢她的打扮
I like her style.
-谢天谢地你终于回来了 -发生什么事了
- Thank Goodness you're back! - What's the matter?
戴维斯那的一个伙计刚刚来了
A lad from Davis's came round.
他们会计部门有点困难
They have a problem in their accounts department
-想让你马上过去 -就这样吗
- And they need you up there straight away. - Is that all?
-那我先把买来的东西放起来 -不不不 我来
- I'll just put the shopping away. - No, no, leave it.
那小伙子说的是 马上
“Straight away”, the young fella said.
他说什么不重要 母亲 我又不是那里的职员
It doesn't matter what he said, Mother. I'm not an employee.
我要去也只是帮个忙
I'd be doing them a favour.
你就让我来放这些行吗
Please let me do the shopping.
麻烦的是 现在是我们的忙季
The problem is that it's our busy season,
所有的中层工人和司机上周都在加班
so all the middle workers and drivers did overtime last week.
他们已经把加班的单子填好了
Well, they filled out the overtime slips
但是还没人能算出来加班费
but there's been nobody to work it all out,
加到他们的工资单
to add to the wage slips.
有些人已经开始抱怨这事了
And some of the men have started to complain.
我也不怪他们
And I can't blame them.
就像你看到的一样 这儿一团糟
As you can see, it's all a terrible mess.
这样 你给我几个小时 我能整理出一个系统来
Well. If you leave me for a couple of hours, I can work out a system
这样不管是谁来接我的班都不会有任何问题
so that whoever comes in after me won't have any trouble.
你好 艾莉丝
Hello, Eilis.
玛利亚一直在跟我讲你的工作有多么的出色
Maria has been telling me you have done the most marvellous job here.
谢谢
Thank you.
我们理应早就知道你的
We should have known you would, of course.
毕竟你是露丝的妹妹
You're Rose's sister, after all.
有人告诉我你有会计证书是吗
I'm told you have a certificate in book-keeping?
是美国的会计证书吗
Is it in American book-keeping?
我是在美国拿的证书
I got the certificate in America,
但是这两个体系是非常相似的
but the two systems are very similar.
我们在忙季确实需要找会计处理工资和其他事务的
Well, we'll certainly need someone to deal with wages and so on during the busy season.
我希望你能继续在这里兼职
so I'd like you to continue on a part-time basis.
我们可以看看情况 之后我们再谈
Let's see how that goes and then we'll speak again.
我不久以后就会回美国了
I'll be going back to the United States soon.
我说了 在我们彼此都做了最后决定之前
As I said. Lets you and I speak again before we make
我们可以再谈一次
any firm decisions one way or the other.
好的 一定 布朗先生 谢谢
Yes, Mr. Brown. Of course. Thank you.
你现在可以去找玛利亚拿你今天的工资了
Now, if you go and see Maria, she'll have your money for today.
-我都要忘记了 -忘记什么
- I'd forgotten. - What?
眼前的景色
This…
布鲁克林有海滩吗
You have beaches in Brooklyn?
有 但海滩上有很多人
Yes, but they are just very crowded.
过一会儿这里也会有挺多散步的人的
There will probably be quite a few walkers along here later.
是吧 不过还是不一样
Yes. It's still not the same.
那确实
I'm sure it's not.
我们不太知道除了这里其他地方都发生了什么事
We don't really know anything of the rest of the world.
你现在肯定觉得我们很闭塞吧
We must seem very backward to you now.
当然没有 你是个很冷静很有教养的人 很有魅力
Of course not. You seem calm, and civilised. And charming.
快来呀
Come on!
我母亲想让你知道 她们的高尔夫俱乐部
My mother wanted you to know that the golf club…
以露丝的名义设立了一个奖项
is inaugurating a prize in Rose's name.
一个给俱乐部的新人设立的最佳得分奖
A special trophy for the best score by a lady newcomer at the Club.
我母亲说 你姐姐总是对新人很友善
She was always very nice to the newcomers, my mother says.
我希望这能让你开心
I hope you're pleased.
当然
Yes, of course.
所以说 每一年会有人得到一个露丝·蕾西奖
So, every year, someone will win the Rose Lacey Trophy?
每年都有 只要高尔夫俱乐部还存在
Every year. As long as there's a golf club.
她希望第一届你能去给获奖者颁奖
And I think she'd like you to come along and present it to the first winner.
对了 我母亲也想顺便见见你
Yeah and my mother would like to meet you too, by the way.
我会安排一个时间请你来喝茶
I'm supposed to arrange a time when you can come around for tea.
谢谢你 我会去的
Thank you, I'd like that.
要是我走之前就能像现在这样就好了
I wish it had been like this before I went.
-露丝死之前   -像什么样
- Before Rose died. - Like what?
之前我什么都没有 而现在 我有了一份工作 还...
There was nothing here for me here before. And now I have a job, and…
这里行吗
Here?
-这是美国人的方法吗    -是的 不错呢 是吧
- Is that an American trick? - Yes. It’s a good one, isn’t it?
这让人挺郁闷的 我们怎么就想不出这样的方法呢
It's depressing, though, that we don't think of things like that, isn't it?
我是说 他们多久前就想到了
I mean how long have they known about it?
说不定都一百年了
A hundred years, probably.
我觉得一百年前他们应该还没有这样的泳衣吧
I don't think they had bathing suits like that a hundred years ago.
可我们现在都还没有呢
And we still don't have them now.
唉 来吧
Well, come on.
你周六想去看道奇队的球赛吗
You want to go see the Dodgers on Saturday?
当然了
Sure.
行 那你帮我做件事行吗
Okay, will you do something for me?
什么事
What?
如果你嘲笑我 或者跟家里任何一个人说起这件事
If you laugh, or you say anything about this to anybody in the family,
周六的比赛你就没得看了
you don't get to see the Dodgers on Saturday.
这赛季任何一场球你都看不了了
Or any other day of the season.
而且 我还会打你一顿
Also, you get a beating.
那我还是不掺合比较好
Maybe it's just better if I don't get involved.
弗兰基 我真的很需要你帮忙
I really need your help Frankie.
你知道你是这个家里读写能力最好的人
You know you're the best writer and reader in the family?
我知道
Yes.
我试着给艾莉丝写信 我也说不清该怎么写
I'm trying to write to Eilis, and I want it to be, I don't know ...
你之前不是写过了吗 大概五封信
You wrote before already. About five times.
是的 弗兰基 但是它们都不够好
Yeah, but they are no good Frankie and ...
而且她只回过一次信
And she's only written back once.
她之前从未读过我写的东西 我怕她看了会嫌弃我
She's never read my writing before. I'm worried I'm putting her off me.
听着 我才八岁 我才不懂你们亲亲的事
Listen, I'm eight years old, I don't know anything about kissing.
你不需要知道这些事情
You don't need to know anything about kissing.
你只需知道拼写 还有
You need to know about spelling and...and...
-语法吗 -没错 你帮不帮我看
- Grammar? - Yeah, Will you look?
亲爱的艾莉丝 我希望你在爱尔兰一切安好
Dear Eilis, I hope that you're doing well in Ireland.
我希望你的母亲没那么伤心了
I hope that your mother is feeling less sad.
你的朋友很快就会完婚 你就能回到这里了
It will not be long before your friend gets married and you can come home.
这一周好像全世界的地下室都发了大水
This week it is like the whole world's basements are flooding.
我修了三家 我一直在努力工作攒钱
I fixed three. I've been working hard. I've been saving money.
大家都时常向我问起你
Everybody asks me about you all the time.
你单词拼错了 少了一个E
You missed out the "e" I think. It is "everybody."
这大概就是我所有的新鲜事了吧
Anyway, I think that is all my news.
我的父母还有兄弟们都问你好
Mom and dad and all my brothers they all say hello.
我每时每刻都在思念着你
I think about you most minutes of most days.
甚至当我在看道奇队的比赛时
Even when I go see the Dodgers.
我心思都不在球赛上
I do not concentrate on the game.
爱你的托尼
With love, your Tony.
你没有上发油
No hair oil.
还有这不是休闲外套 这是运动夹克
And that's not a blazer, it's a sports jacket.
吉姆·法瑞尔 你是不是穿上了伪装
Have you come out in disguise, Jim Farrell?
你是想诱骗我吗
Are you trying to trick me?
当你说我们那群人是一路货色的时候 我明白你的意思
I knew what you meant, when you said we're all the same.
或许在你看来 我生活地非常容易
It made me think that my life must seem very east to you.
接管父亲的酒吧 住在父母的房子里
I run my father's bar, going to live in my parents' house.
我能想象到外人是怎么看待这一切的
I know what that must look like from the outside
但其实并不是那样
But it doesn't feel like that.
那是什么样的
What does it feel like?
我从没去过任何地方
I've never been anywhere.
我甚至都没到过英格兰
I have never even been to England.
我想去看看 伦敦 巴黎 还有罗马 纽约
But I'd like to see London, and Paris and Rome. New York.
一想到我这辈子可能都踏不出爱尔兰 就觉得可怕
It frightens me, the idea of dying without ever leaving Ireland.
当然还有些别的事情
And there are other things too ...
抱歉 我想问你很多事 但我却一直在说
I'm so sorry. I wanted to ask you a thousand things and all I've done is talked.
没事 我喜欢听
I am glad.
-真的吗   -真的
- Really? - Yes.
你能快点抽完你那破烟 然后过来坐下吗
Will you finsh that wretched pipe and sit with us?
我在这儿也听得一清二楚
I can hear perfectly well from where I am.
我们可不是来给你提供娱乐节目的
We are not here to provide you with entertainment.
别担心 很多年前我就明白这个道理了
Oh, don't you worry. I found that out many years ago.
艾莉丝 你别理他 反正吉姆像我 不随他
Just ignore him, Eilis. It's as well Jim takes after me, but him.
你大声点
Speak up!
你们期待搬家吗
Are you looking forward to your move?
我会想念恩尼斯科西的 但是格伦布里恩是个美丽安宁的地方
Ah, I will miss Enniscorthy. But it's lovely and quiet in Glenbrien.
我妈担心我一个人在这
My mother's worried about leaving me here on me own.
她怕我会毁了这地方
She thinks I'll destroy the place.
我希望你不要单身一辈子
I'm hoping you won't be on your own forever.
我相信他不会的
I'm sure he won't.
我的意思是
I mean...
-今天天气真好不是吗    -是个好天气
- God, aren't we blessed with this weather. - It's lovely.
亲爱的托尼 感谢你的来信
Dear Tony, thank you for your letters.
我想要你知道
I want you to know that...
我不知道我想跟你说啥
I don't know what I want you to know.
我不想坐在很后面的位置
I don't want to be sitting right at the back.
我会确保你们坐在教堂最好的位置
I'll make sure you get the best seats in the house.
但是坐在南希和乔治边上也很奇怪
Oh, it wouldn't feel right sitting up there with Nancy and George.
那我们就坐在教堂内第二好的位置上
We'll find the second best seats in the house then.
我先去为你们留个好位置可以吗 蕾西太太
Would you like me to run ahead and save you a couple of places, Mrs. Lacey?
不麻烦你吗吉姆 那真是太好了
Would you mind Jim? That would be grand.
-真是一位绅士 不是嘛  -没错
- Such a gentleman, isn't he? - He is.
他在最合适的时间出现在我们身边
He came along at just the right time for us.
南希 我诚邀你在这教堂里宣誓 在上帝的见证下
I invite you now Nancy, to declare before God and his church ...
成为乔治的妻子
your consent to become George's wife.
我发誓 无论顺境还是逆境
I promise to be true to you in good times and in bad,
无论疾病还是健康 我都会爱着你
in sickness and in health. I will love you
尊重你 在我生命的每一天
and honour you all the days of my life.
拿戒指来
The rings.
主啊 请赐福这对戒指 戴上这对戒指的新人
Lord, bless these rings, grant that those who wear them
能永远对彼此忠诚
may always be faithful to each other.
愿他们遵从神意 和睦相爱
May they do your will and live in peace with you, and mutual love.
请遵从主的圣意 阿门
We ask this through Christ our Lord. Amen.
阿门
Amen.
艾莉丝 听你妈说 你在这儿过的很好
Your mother tells me things are working out for you very well in Enniscorthy, Eilis.
婚礼仪式办得很好
It was a lovely service.
听说法瑞尔夫妇就要搬去格伦布里恩 吉姆就...
And Mr and Mrs Farrell are moving out to Glenbrien, so Jim will...
是的 我知道
Yes, I know.
吉姆和我答应要带我妈回车上
Jim and I promised my mother we'd take her back to the car.
哦 听到了吗 吉姆和我 吉姆和我
Oh, do you hear that? “Jim and I! Jim and I!”.
听你这么说 感觉好事将近了呢
It won't be long now, by the sound of it,
你妈妈一定会很开心
and your mother will have a wonderful day out.
抱歉 我先走一步
Will you excuse me?
我们能谈一谈吗
Can we talk?
-关于什么    -关于未来
- What about? - The future.
我不能一句话不说就让你回美国了
I can't let you just go back to America without saying anything.
这样的话 我会后悔一辈子的
I'd regret it for the rest of my life.
所以我想说 我不想让你走
So, I don't want you to go.
我想你留在这里 和我在一起
I want you to stay here, with me.
我知道这意味着 我要问你另外一个问题
And I know that means asking you another question,
我并不想吓到你
But I don't want to bombard you.
所以我决定迟一些再问你
So I'll save that one for later.
谢谢你
Thank you.
我很感激 也很受宠若惊
I'm grateful. And I'm flattered.
-就这些了吗 -不
- That's all? - No.
当然不是
No, of course not.
只是
It is just...
我想象的是完全不同的另一种生活
I'd imagined a different life for myself.
我理解你
I understand.
但是你在这的生活 也可以一样好
But your life here could be just as good.
甚至是更好
Better,even, maybe.
玛丽
Mary!
我是来请你去一趟的
I was just coming to fetch you.
为什么要叫我去 我已经不在凯莉夫人那里工作很久了 玛丽
To fetch me? I haven't worked for Miss Kelly for a long time, Mary.
拜托了 艾莉丝 她说让我不接到你就别回去
Oh, Please come Eilis. She told me not to come back without you.
你知道她是什么样的人
You know what she's like.
玛丽 我上楼和艾莉丝谈话的时候你替我照看一下店 就五分钟
You look after things for five minutes while I'm upstairs with Eilis, please, Mary.
这个时候店里没什么顾客
There are no customers in there at the moment,
我觉得你应该不会搞得太糟
so I don't think you can make too much of a mess of things.
所以 你近来如何呀
So. How have you been getting on?
谢谢凯莉夫人 一切都很好
Very well, thanks, Miss Kelly.
我听说你在戴维斯那工作
I heard that you're working over at Davis's?
在会计部门
In the accounts department?
是的
That's right.
我听到很多关于你和吉姆·法瑞尔的流言蜚语
And there's lots of talk about you and young Jim Farrell.
你知道人们就热衷于说三道四
Ah, well. You know what people are like. They love to talk.
这倒是真的 你还记得布雷迪太太吗
Yes. Do you remember Mrs. Brady?
她以前常在周日早上来店里买些熏肉片
She usually comes into the shop on Sunday morning for her rashers.
不记得了吗 看来你现在过的很繁忙啊
No? Well, you have a very busy life now.
一桩接一桩
What with one thing and another.
布雷迪太太有个侄女住在布鲁克林
Anyway, Mrs Brady has a niece living in Brooklyn.
这个世界真小 不是嘛
The world is a small place, isn't it?
她几周前收到她侄女的一封信
She had a letter from her a couple of weeks back.
那信上怎么说
And what did it say?
就是说她去市政厅参加别人的婚礼
Oh, only that she'd been to a wedding at the city hall,
她丈夫无意中撞见一个来自恩尼斯科西的女孩也在那里登记结婚
and her husband bumped into a girl from Enniscorthy who was getting married there.
凯莉夫人 我不太懂你到底想表达什么
I'm not sure what you're telling me, Miss Kelly.
他没有撞见我
He didn't bump into me.
蕾西小姐 你可糊弄不了我
Oh, you can't fool me, Miss Lacey.
我都不确定这还是你的姓氏吗
Although I'm not sure that that's your name any longer, is it?
他已经记不太清了 好像姓是意大利的
He couldn't remember. Something Italian, he thought.
我忘了
I'd forgotten.
你居然说你忘了 这真是
You'd forgotten! What a thing for...
我是说 我忘了这个镇是什么样的了
I'd forgotten what this town is like.
凯莉夫人 你到底在打什么小主意
What were you planning to do, Miss Kelly?
想让我离吉姆远一点吗
Keep me away from Jim?
还是想阻止我回美国
Stop me from going back to America?
或许你自己都不知道
Perhaps you didn't even know.
我的名字是艾莉丝·菲欧雷洛
My name is Eilis Fiorello.
-谢谢 -你好 有什么可以帮您的
- Thank you. - How I can help you?
你好 我想预订一张最近一班从科夫到纽约的船票
Hello, I'd like to make a reservation for the next available sailing from Cobh to New York.
我觉得婚礼后反而更花钱
I think people spend even more money after a wedding.
南希的妈妈该是把镇上所有店走了遍吧
Nancy's mother must have been in every shop in the town.
她连点火器都买好了
She was buying firelighters in Broom's.
在八月就买点火器
Firelighters! In August!
但是她见了斯泰普尔顿太太
But she'd seen Mrs. Stapleton in there,
她还没有机会把婚礼一整天的细节都和她过一遍
and she hadn't had a chance to go through the whole day in detail with her, so...
艾莉丝 你怎么了
Eilis, what's the matter?
你和吉姆之间发生什么了吗
Has something happened with Jim?
妈 我很抱歉
Mommy, I'm sorry.
我非常抱歉 我已经结婚了
I'm so sorry. I'm married.
我回家之前就在布鲁克林完婚了 我应该告诉你的
I got married in Brooklyn before I came home. I should have told you.
我应该回来第一时间告诉你
I should have told you as soon as I got back.
我想和他 和我的丈夫在一起
I want to be with him. I want to be with my husband.
那是当然
Of course.
他人好吗
Is he nice?
很好
Yes.
你嫁的人一定是很好的
He'd have to be nice, if you married him.
所以你要回纽约去吗
So you are going back?
是的 就是明天
Yes. Tomorrow.
你是要坐早班的火车吗
Are you on the early train?
我要去睡觉了
I'm going to bed.
妈 现在连八点都没到 你不要这样
Mummy...It's not even eight o'clock. You don't have to..
我很疲倦
I'm very tired.
我想现在就说再见 只说一次
And I'd like to say goodbye now, and only once.
或许你能在信里跟我聊聊他
Perhaps you'll write and tell me about him.
我会的
I will.
艾莉丝 晚安
Goodnight Eilis.
你是要搬去美国吗
So are you away to live in America?
-不是 -去旅游嘛
- No. - Just visiting?
不是 我已经住在那儿了
No. I live there already.
真的吗 那是什么感觉
Really? What's it like?
那是一个很大很大的地方
It's a big place.
我准备住在纽约的布鲁克林 你知道那吗
I'm gonna live in Brooklyn, New York. Do you know it?
当然
Yes.
人们都说 在那里有很多爱尔兰人
People say that there's so many Irish people there.
就像家一样
It's like home.
这是真的吗
Is that right?
是真的 就像家一样
Yes, it's just like home.
你不准吃东西
You're not to eat.
但是我得在那儿待好久啊
But I might be there years.
你到美国后就什么都能吃
No, you can eat when you get there.
但千万别在船上吃东西
Don't eat on the boat.
这样就不晕船了 你能答应我吗
It'll stop you getting so sick. Do you promise me?
我答应
I promise.
过会儿 你马上到你的房间
And in a moment, I want you to go straight down to your cabin
然后把你这侧的门锁上
and lock the bathroom door on your side.
等隔壁房间开始砸门 你就可以开始谈判
When next door starts hammering, you can negotiate.
等你到了海关那儿 睁大你的眼睛
When you get to Immigration, keep your eyes wide open,
摆出你知道自己要去哪儿的样子
Look as if you know where you're going.
你必须像美国人一样思考
You have to think like an American.
麻烦你上前一步
Could you please step forward?
你会十分想家 想得要命
You'll feel so homesick that you'll want to die,
你除了忍受这一切以外毫无办法
and there's nothing you can do about it apart from endure it.
但是这一切并不会击垮你
But you will, and it won't kill you.
终有一天 太阳会再次升起
And one day the sun will come out
你或许都未曾注意到 就这么悄无声息地
and you might not even note it straight away, it would be that faint.
你会开始思考其它的事情
And then you will catch yourself thinking about something or
会挂念一个和你过去毫无交集的人
or someone who has no connection with the past,
一个只属于你的人
Someone who's only yours.
那时 你就会明白
And you'll realise
这就是你的安生之地
that this is where your life is.